<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Jie Liu</title>
    <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Jie Liu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Jie Liu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jieliu6.github.io/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography I received my Ph.D. in computer science from the University of Wisconsin-Madison. I am currently a postdoctoral fellow in the Genome Sciences Department at the University of Washington. My research areas are machine learning and its applications in biomedical informatics.
I will join as an assistant professor in the Department of Computational Medicine and Bioinformatics  at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor in January 2019. Interested students/postdocs can reach out to me via email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service</title>
      <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/service/</guid>
      <description>Journal Referee Journal of the American Statistical Association, Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery, Machine Learning, Genome Research, Cell Systems, Bioinformatics, Pattern Recognition Letters, Journal of Digital Imaging, Economic Modelling
Conference Program Committee ICLR 2019, AMIA Informatics Summit 2019, NIPS 2018, ISMB 2018, AMIA 2018, ICML 2018, RECOMB 2018, ICLR 2018, AMIA Informatics Summit 2018, NIPS-MLCB 2017, NIPS 2017, AMIA 2017, AMIA-TBI/CRI 2017, AAAI 2017, NIPS 2016, AMIA 2016, AAAI 2016, AMIA-TBI/CRI 2016, ACMBCB 2016, MLSB 2016, NIPS 2015, IJCAI 2015, AMIA 2015, AMIA-TBI/CRI 2015, AISTATS 2015, WABI2015, NIPS 2014, UAI 2014, AAAI 2014, AMIA 2014, IJCAI 2013, AMIA 2013, GENSIPS 2012</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awards</title>
      <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/awards/</guid>
      <description> (2015) Washington Research Foundation Innovation Postdoctoral Fellowship (2014) AMIA Marco Ramoni Distinguished Paper Award (2014) Moore/Sloan Data Science Postdoctoral Fellowship  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description> Courses  Guest instructor, CS 760 Machine Learning, UW-Madison, 2014 Spring. Guest instructor, STAT 992 Large-scale inference, UW-Madison, 2013 Spring. Teaching assistant, Introduction to Artificial Intelligence, Peking University, 2005 Spring.  Mentees  John T Halloran, PhD student, Department of Electrical Engineering, University of Washington Charles Kwong, PhD student, Department of Computer Sciences, UW-Madison Sinong Geng, Graduate student, Department of Statistics, UW-Madison  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jieliu6.github.io/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>