<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Liu Lab</title>
    <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Liu Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2020 Jie Liu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jieliu6.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>single-cell multi-omics integration</title>
      <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/project/single-cell-multi-omics-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jieliu6.github.io/project/single-cell-multi-omics-integration/</guid>
      <description>Many single-cell sequencing technologies are now available, but it is still difficult to apply multiple sequencing technologies to the same single cell. In this paper, we propose an unsupervised manifold alignment algorithm, MMD-MA, for integrating multiple measurements carried out on disjoint aliquots of a given population of cells. Effectively, MMD-MA performs an in silico co-assay by embedding cells measured in different ways into a learned latent space. In the MMD-MA algorithm, single-cell data points from multiple domains are aligned by optimizing an objective function with three components: (1) a maximum mean discrepancy (MMD) term to encourage the differently measured points to have similar distributions in the latent space, (2) a distortion term to preserve the structure of the data between the input space and the latent space, and (3) a penalty term to avoid collapse to a trivial solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scHi-C embedding</title>
      <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/project/hic-embedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jieliu6.github.io/project/hic-embedding/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell Hi-C (scHi-C) data promises to enable scientists to interrogate the 3D architecture of DNA in the nucleus of the cell, studying how this structure varies stochastically or along developmental or cell cycle axes. However, Hi-C data analysis requires methods that take into account the unique characteristics of this type of data. In this work, we explore whether methods that have been developed previously for the analysis of bulk Hi-C data can be applied to scHi-C data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Testing Under Dependence</title>
      <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/project/multiple-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jieliu6.github.io/project/multiple-testing/</guid>
      <description>Observations from large-scale multiple testing problems often exhibit dependence in the sense that whether the null hypothesis of one test is true or not (termed underlying true state) depends on the underlying true states of other tests. For instance, in genome-wide association studies, researchers collect hundreds of thousands of highly correlated genetic markers (single-nucleotide polymorphisms, or SNPs) with the purpose of identifying the subset of markers associated with a heritable disease or trait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalized Breast Cancer Diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/project/radiogenomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jieliu6.github.io/project/radiogenomics/</guid>
      <description>+++
High hopes for using genetic profiling for personalized medicine have been, in part, driven by the rapid progress of genome-wide association studies, which continue identifying more common genetic variants associated with diseases with high population prevalence. In particular, the recent Collaborative Oncological Gene-environment Study (COGS), which pooled large quantities of genetic data via a massive international collaboration, more than doubled the number of known susceptibility loci that are associated to common cancers (breast, ovarian and prostate cancers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tumor Heterogeneity Anaysis</title>
      <link>https://jieliu6.github.io/project/themis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jieliu6.github.io/project/themis/</guid>
      <description>Cancer is heterogeneous in the sense that the cancer cells in a tumor are not genetically identical, but form distinct clones, defined as subpopulations of cancer cells that host the same genomic aberrations. In aggressive and metastatic cancers, these genomic aberrations quickly evolve, resulting in extreme spatial and temporal heterogeneity (Shah et al. 2012, Nowell 1976). Therefore, multiple biopsies over different locations and at different time points need to be collected and sequenced in order to capture the complexity of tumor genomic landscapes and provide insight into how tumors evolve and escape treatment (Gerlinger et al.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>